hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the Tosca automation playlist
so continuing with our automation
obstacles for Tosca we are looking at
the third obstacle and this one is
marked as hard so there would be some
challenge in this particular obstacle so
let's see what this obstacle is
so here uh it is saying let's assume
your application as a test generates an
offer ID every time you click on the
according button so this particular
button uh unfortunately it gets added to
the table randomly
find a way to automate a stable test
step that clicks the button okay and
then buffers the generated offer ID and
enter it into the text box
the test steps needs to run every time
okay so
here there will be an order ID which
will be added into this particular table
as a row okay so when we click on this
generate order ID
so you can see here this is the order ID
which has been generated now we need to
select this and then enter it here okay
and then this particular riddle will be
solved so
but the problem is when we click on this
generate order ID okay so this time you
see it is added here
the next time it will be added here okay
so the position is not consistent it is
changing the row number uh every time
okay so that's the problem here and
that's the challenge actually which you
need to solve okay
so if you already know the solution then
go ahead and complete this challenge
if not I am going to tell you
um how you should solve this particular
challenge
okay so first let's go ahead and
go into the modules and let's go into
obstacles and then we are going to scan
this particular application
okay so I'm going to scan this
and here uh currently it is not showing
me that particular table as you can see
here so I'm going to increase the
filtered items
and then
I am going to come here and
and then we are going to look for the
order ID okay so this is the order ID
you can see here
and as you can see
um it's not actually a table okay it
looks like a table on the page but it is
not because it doesn't contain any rows
and tables everything is a div element
so you need to consider this as a Dev
element
now here is the order you can see here
order number right
but if we go ahead and select this
element
So currently this order number is
present but the next time we click on
generating the order
then the order number will change also
in this particular element will not be
in this same position so our test case
will obviously fail okay
now what you need to do here is first of
all we need to remove this in a text
because this inner text is dynamically
changing okay so we cannot use this we
can use the tag div but as soon as we
remove the inner text our item becomes
or the element becomes uh not unique
right so Tosca now cannot identify this
element because everything is a div tag
right here
so in this case
um obviously when we don't have any
properties to fall back up on uh we have
to change the identification mechanism
right so instead of properties now let's
go ahead and look out for identifier by
anchor okay so change the identification
method okay so let's choose anchor
and now we are going to look out for
anchor control so the best possible
anchor control here could be the order
ID right so this is also development and
no matter where this order ID is placed
in this particular table
it will always be besides this number
the order ID value right
so this is the best possible anchor
control through which you can identify
this uh control which is the actual
order ID
okay
so here what we are going to do is I'm
going to drag this order ID
and place it in the anchor control
and now you will see that the selected
item is unique okay so using that order
ID text we are identifying the actual
order number okay
so we are using that text as an anchor
control to identify the other control
basically
so let's now decrease this filtered
items and now I also want to select the
generate order ID link and the text box
so these are the three controls which I
want
I'm going to save this and close this
and come here I'm going to rename this
module first
okay and here
and now uh since I selected this order
ID control first it is here
but I need to make sure that my test
steps are in the right order right so
first I need to click on this link then
I need to buffer this or somehow store
this somewhere and then I need to enter
this into the text box okay
so we are going to rename this because
this is not the order ID which we'll be
getting so I am going to rename it to
order ID
so here I'm going to create a test case
so let's create a test case here and
then I'm going to rename this
and then I'm going to drag my module
here right now we have solved uh the
first problem which is to basically find
out where this particular order is and
we can identify this element the next
challenge is to buffer the generated
offer ID okay and enter it into this
edit box so it's quite simple to buffer
that okay so first we are going to click
on this
and then we are going to buffer this so
I will change the actual mode to buffer
here
and I am going to select inner text
because the inner text will actually
contain the order ID
and then I am going to name it order ID
here
and then here I'm going to use the
buffer value okay
so order ID
okay so this is my test tip you can see
here first it is clicking on this link
then it is identifying this element
getting the inner text and storing it in
a buffer uh name called order ID
and that buffer will contain the actual
order ID value which I can use it to
enter it into the text field okay so
that's the logic which you need to
implement here
now let's go here and we'll change the
workstate to complete it and then we are
going to run this quickly
okay so as you can see uh it grabbed the
order ID and then it entered it into the
text box okay so the order ID generated
is the same which we have entered here
which means our challenge has been
completed okay
so I would say this was a good obstacle
um to practice and you will face this
kind of challenges a lot of times in
your application
so this is how you can basically uh find
out a element which doesn't have any
properties using the identify by anchor
method and then you can buffer the value
which you have selected and then you can
enter it into the edit box okay so all
three steps have been covered here
that's all for this particular video if
you have any questions then please leave
it in the comments if you like this
video then please subscribe to our
Channel
thanks for watching and I will see you
in the next video